<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Academia | Juan Cruz-Benito</title>
    <link>https://cbjuan.github.io/tag/academia/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://cbjuan.github.io/tag/academia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Academia</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://cbjuan.github.io/img/JuanCruzBenito_square.jpg</url>
      <title>Academia</title>
      <link>https://cbjuan.github.io/tag/academia/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Returning to the University of Salamanca: Sharing My PhD Journey</title>
      <link>https://cbjuan.github.io/post/2025-university-salamanca-phd-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cbjuan.github.io/post/2025-university-salamanca-phd-talk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was a special day returning to my alma mater, the University of Salamanca to share my journey with current PhD students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking about my PhD experience and the career path that followed felt like coming full circle. It was inspiring to connect with brilliant doctoral candidates who are navigating their own research journeys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My main message? Make the most of your PhD years - they&amp;rsquo;re not just about the research, but about developing the critical thinking, resilience, and problem-solving skills that will serve you throughout your career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The energy and curiosity of the audience brought back memories of my own PhD days, which were truly an adventure. Getting to hang out with fellow PhD students and other speakers made the experience even more enriching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A heartfelt thank you to Universidad de Salamanca, the Escuela de Doctorado and Alicia G. for the invitation and for creating such valuable spaces for knowledge sharing and mentorship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s to supporting the next generation of researchers! 🎓&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#PhD #UniversityOfSalamanca #Academia #Research #Mentorship #DoctoralStudies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally shared on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/juancb_phd-universityofsalamanca-academia-activity-7337014939938664449-BkP8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; on June 7, 2025 - 115 reactions, 1 comment as of 11/12/2025&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
