<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Future Tech | Juan Cruz-Benito</title>
    <link>https://cbjuan.github.io/tag/future-tech/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://cbjuan.github.io/tag/future-tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Future Tech</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2026 Juan Cruz-Benito</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://cbjuan.github.io/img/JuanCruzBenito_square.jpg</url>
      <title>Future Tech</title>
      <link>https://cbjuan.github.io/tag/future-tech/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Among IBM Giants and Pioneers: Reflections from IBM Tech 2025 in Singapore</title>
      <link>https://cbjuan.github.io/post/2025-ibm-tech-singapore/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cbjuan.github.io/post/2025-ibm-tech-singapore/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Among 👁️🐝Ⓜ️ Giants and Pioneers: Reflections from IBM Tech 2025 in Singapore 🇸🇬&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had the privilege of attending IBM Tech 2025 in Singapore this week - an exclusive, invitation-only gathering of IBM&amp;rsquo;s top technical talent from around the world. As one of the selected participants, I&amp;rsquo;m humbled to have been recognized among IBM&amp;rsquo;s most innovative and performing technical minds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The atmosphere was electric as we dove deep into the future of AI, quantum computing, and emerging technologies. What struck me most was not just the cutting-edge content of the presentations from colleagues and leaders such as Ruchir Puri, Suja Viswesan, Ric Lewis, Borja Peropadre, and others, but the quality of conversations happening between sessions. Exchanging ideas with brilliant colleagues across different technical disciplines provided invaluable perspective on where technology is headed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Particularly enlightening were the discussions with my IBM Quantum and AI Research colleagues and the cross-pollination of ideas between different technical domains. These connections reinforced my belief that the most transformative innovations happen at the intersection of diverse expertise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond the technical exchanges, Singapore provided a stunning backdrop for cultural experiences that complemented our professional activities. The city&amp;rsquo;s blend of tradition and futuristic vision perfectly mirrored our discussions about building tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s technologies while honoring established principles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Returning home energized and inspired, I&amp;rsquo;m grateful for both the recognition and the opportunity to contribute to IBM&amp;rsquo;s technical community. The future belongs to those who collaborate across boundaries, and IBM Tech 2025 demonstrated that our collective expertise is our greatest strength.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#IBMTech2025 #Innovation #TechnicalExcellence #QuantumComputing #AI #FutureTech #IBMLife #AIforQuantum&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally shared on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/juancb_ibmtech2025-innovation-technicalexcellence-activity-7311293166270242817-FcdZ&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; on March 28, 2025 - 96 reactions, 14 comments as of 11/12/2025&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
