<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Innovation | Juan Cruz-Benito</title>
    <link>https://cbjuan.github.io/tag/innovation/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://cbjuan.github.io/tag/innovation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Innovation</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2026 Juan Cruz-Benito</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://cbjuan.github.io/img/JuanCruzBenito_square.jpg</url>
      <title>Innovation</title>
      <link>https://cbjuan.github.io/tag/innovation/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keynote Speaker at Metafuturo 2025: Quantum Computing &#43; AI Convergence</title>
      <link>https://cbjuan.github.io/post/2025-metafuturo-quantum-ai-keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cbjuan.github.io/post/2025-metafuturo-quantum-ai-keynote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;🚀 Thrilled to have been part of Metafuturo 2025 as a keynote speaker!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had the incredible opportunity to share insights on the convergence of Quantum Computing + AI at this forward-thinking event organized by Bizkaiko Foru Aldundia / Diputación Foral de Bizkaia and ATRESMEDIA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The intersection of quantum technologies and artificial intelligence represents one of the most exciting frontiers in tech today. During my talk, I shared what we are doing in this field at IBM Quantum. From LLMs and agentic AI applications for quantum computing to AI-optimized quantum circuits, we&amp;rsquo;re witnessing the birth of computational capabilities that seemed like science fiction just a few years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What struck me most during the event was the genuine curiosity and engagement from attendees across diverse industries. The talks and panels ranged from practical implementations to philosophical implications—exactly the kind of multidisciplinary dialogue we need as we navigate this quantum journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huge thanks to the organizers for creating such a vibrant platform for discussing the technologies that will shape our tomorrow. Events like Metafuturo 2025 are essential for building bridges between cutting-edge research and real-world applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The future is quantum-enhanced, AI-powered, and closer than we think! 🔬⚡&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#QuantumComputing #ArtificialIntelligence #Innovation #Metafuturo2025 #TechTrends #QuantumAI #FutureOfTech #IBM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally shared on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/juancb_quantumcomputing-artificialintelligence-innovation-activity-7376756582644166656-N5v6&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; on September 24, 2025 - 107 reactions, 7 comments as of 11/12/2025&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Among IBM Giants and Pioneers: Reflections from IBM Tech 2025 in Singapore</title>
      <link>https://cbjuan.github.io/post/2025-ibm-tech-singapore/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cbjuan.github.io/post/2025-ibm-tech-singapore/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Among 👁️🐝Ⓜ️ Giants and Pioneers: Reflections from IBM Tech 2025 in Singapore 🇸🇬&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had the privilege of attending IBM Tech 2025 in Singapore this week - an exclusive, invitation-only gathering of IBM&amp;rsquo;s top technical talent from around the world. As one of the selected participants, I&amp;rsquo;m humbled to have been recognized among IBM&amp;rsquo;s most innovative and performing technical minds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The atmosphere was electric as we dove deep into the future of AI, quantum computing, and emerging technologies. What struck me most was not just the cutting-edge content of the presentations from colleagues and leaders such as Ruchir Puri, Suja Viswesan, Ric Lewis, Borja Peropadre, and others, but the quality of conversations happening between sessions. Exchanging ideas with brilliant colleagues across different technical disciplines provided invaluable perspective on where technology is headed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Particularly enlightening were the discussions with my IBM Quantum and AI Research colleagues and the cross-pollination of ideas between different technical domains. These connections reinforced my belief that the most transformative innovations happen at the intersection of diverse expertise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond the technical exchanges, Singapore provided a stunning backdrop for cultural experiences that complemented our professional activities. The city&amp;rsquo;s blend of tradition and futuristic vision perfectly mirrored our discussions about building tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s technologies while honoring established principles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Returning home energized and inspired, I&amp;rsquo;m grateful for both the recognition and the opportunity to contribute to IBM&amp;rsquo;s technical community. The future belongs to those who collaborate across boundaries, and IBM Tech 2025 demonstrated that our collective expertise is our greatest strength.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#IBMTech2025 #Innovation #TechnicalExcellence #QuantumComputing #AI #FutureTech #IBMLife #AIforQuantum&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally shared on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/juancb_ibmtech2025-innovation-technicalexcellence-activity-7311293166270242817-FcdZ&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; on March 28, 2025 - 96 reactions, 14 comments as of 11/12/2025&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Honored to Receive IBM Master Inventor Recognition</title>
      <link>https://cbjuan.github.io/post/2024-ibm-master-inventor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cbjuan.github.io/post/2024-ibm-master-inventor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m honored to share that I&amp;rsquo;ve received the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.credly.com/badges/cf8bd032-f112-4b81-9439-41011b83c090&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;IBM Master Inventor recognition&lt;/a&gt;! 🎉&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This distinction is awarded to employees who have &amp;ldquo;mastered the patent process, mentored broadly, added value to IBM&amp;rsquo;s portfolio and demonstrated sustained innovation leadership and service.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s incredibly rewarding to be recognized for contributions that blend innovation with mentorship and service to the broader community. This achievement reflects not just individual effort, but the collaborative spirit of working with brilliant colleagues across IBM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to everyone who has been part of this journey!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally shared on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/juancb_master-inventor-was-issued-by-ibm-to-juan-activity-7255334536752865282-3tR8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; on October 24, 2024 - 137 reactions, 40 comments as of 11/12/2025&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
