<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tech Trends | Juan Cruz-Benito</title>
    <link>https://cbjuan.github.io/tag/tech-trends/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://cbjuan.github.io/tag/tech-trends/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Tech Trends</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://cbjuan.github.io/img/JuanCruzBenito_square.jpg</url>
      <title>Tech Trends</title>
      <link>https://cbjuan.github.io/tag/tech-trends/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keynote Speaker at Metafuturo 2025: Quantum Computing &#43; AI Convergence</title>
      <link>https://cbjuan.github.io/post/2025-metafuturo-quantum-ai-keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cbjuan.github.io/post/2025-metafuturo-quantum-ai-keynote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;🚀 Thrilled to have been part of Metafuturo 2025 as a keynote speaker!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had the incredible opportunity to share insights on the convergence of Quantum Computing + AI at this forward-thinking event organized by Bizkaiko Foru Aldundia / Diputación Foral de Bizkaia and ATRESMEDIA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The intersection of quantum technologies and artificial intelligence represents one of the most exciting frontiers in tech today. During my talk, I shared what we are doing in this field at IBM Quantum. From LLMs and agentic AI applications for quantum computing to AI-optimized quantum circuits, we&amp;rsquo;re witnessing the birth of computational capabilities that seemed like science fiction just a few years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What struck me most during the event was the genuine curiosity and engagement from attendees across diverse industries. The talks and panels ranged from practical implementations to philosophical implications—exactly the kind of multidisciplinary dialogue we need as we navigate this quantum journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huge thanks to the organizers for creating such a vibrant platform for discussing the technologies that will shape our tomorrow. Events like Metafuturo 2025 are essential for building bridges between cutting-edge research and real-world applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The future is quantum-enhanced, AI-powered, and closer than we think! 🔬⚡&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#QuantumComputing #ArtificialIntelligence #Innovation #Metafuturo2025 #TechTrends #QuantumAI #FutureOfTech #IBM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally shared on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/juancb_quantumcomputing-artificialintelligence-innovation-activity-7376756582644166656-N5v6&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; on September 24, 2025 - 107 reactions, 7 comments as of 11/12/2025&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
